Guide to the Yale Bowl Materials Collected by Charles A. Ferry
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Bowl Materials Collected By Charles A. Ferry
1911-1989
RU 3
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(3 boxes)
The collection consists of documents, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia concerning the building of the Yale Bowl. A small quantity of material documents its later use.
Ferry, Charles Addison, 1852-1924
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ruth Ferry, 1990.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically and by material type.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of documents, photographs, clippings, and memorabilia concerning the building of the Yale Bowl. A small quantity of material documents its later use.
Stadiums -- Design and construction; Architectural records; Photographs; Ferry, Charles Addison, 1852-1924; Yale University -- Football; Yale University -- Sports
- Yale Bowl materials collected by Charles A. Ferry, Series I
  - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proposed Yale Bowl Memorabilia, circa 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs
    - Charles A. Ferry Bowl model, circa 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - First batch of concrete, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Construction album, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Miscellaneous construction, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Bowl filled, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Contracts, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Seating, circa 1914 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia and clipping, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly: Bowl number, 1914 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Pageant, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Paper on the Boal by Charles A. Ferry, circa 1916 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Discussion on the Yale Bowl, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Aerial photograph, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut Tercentenary, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - New Haven Tercentenary Festival Pageant, "Through Many Generations", 1938 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, 1935, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "Pops" concert, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, 1959, 1964, 1981-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 23 - 24)
  - Scrapbook, 1913-1914 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Etching plates (3), undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Photocopied original clippings (restricted) (Box 3)
    Conditions Governing Access
    These records are restricted due to their fragility.